# Luwam Ghide

## Contact

**Address** 

Toronto, ON M3M2R8

**Phone** 

1-437-775-2746

E-mail

ghideluw@gmail.com

#### **Skills**

CSS

HIML

Project Management

API design knowledge

Application development

Database management software

Testing and maintenance

Agile Workflow

Web development projects

**JavaScript** 

Responsive design

Teambuilding

Standard-compliant coding

Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. In-depth knowledge of MySQL and MongoDB, and NoSQL. Able to create servers and databases for functionality and designing and developing APIs. Hardworking collaborator with strong work ethic. Experience in developing and designing web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, and React. Strong commitment to bringing a solutions-oriented problemsolving approach to tasks. Committed to providing a high standard of results for the goal of improved user experience and usability.

## **Work History**

#### 2022-10 -Current

#### **Travel Consultant**

American Express, Toronto, ON

- Informed clients of travel policies and utilized preferred vendors to maximize company profits
- Organized trips for individual, family and business travelers.
- Worked closely with clients to understand unique needs and meet specific travel desires.
- Advised clients on visa, passport and security requirements relating to destinations and confirmed flight details for each reservation.
- Collected, handled and documented payments for travel services and associated feels.
- Handled sensitive information with professionalism and discretion.
- Kept abreast of all airline rules, regulatory requirements and industry standards when scheduling travel arrangements.
- Provided customers with best deals and well-researched travel options, successfully negotiating rates when possible

#### 2021-12 -Current

## **Operations Support**

Ultra Violet Nightclub, Toronto, ON

Collaborated with operations team of up to 5
people to
provide excellent customer service and foster
positive work environment.

- Collected payment of entry fee from patrons accurately and maintained a consistent count of capacity for business needs.
- Maintained a balanced cash drawer at beginning and end of each work shift, ensuring transactions were performed accurately.
- Maintained coat check service to 100 200 patrons in a organized manner ensuring steady and consistent workflow and responsibly maintaining patrons items securely.
- Resolved issues through active listening and open-ended questioning, escalating major problems to manager.

# 2022-02 - Sales Associate

2022-05

Zara, Toronto, ON

- Prepared merchandise for sales floor by pricing or tagging.
- Engaged with customers to build rapport and loyalty.
- Helped customers locate products and checked store system for merchandise at other sites.
- Solved customer challenges by offering relevant products and services.
- Answered customer questions about sizing, accessories and merchandise care.
- Supervised 15 changing rooms, rehanging unwanted merchandise and supporting loss prevention initiatives.
- Organized racks and shelves to maintain store visual appeal, engage customers and promote specific merchandise.
- Maintained calm demeanor and professionally managed issues in busy, high-stress situations.
- Accurately processed POS transactions with \$500 float, returning coin, currency, payment cards and receipts to customers.

# 2017-04 - Ticketing and Customer Service2020-09 Representative

Ink Entertainemnt, Toronto, ON

- Greeted and processed tickets of 1000-3500 patrons at concert and night club events.
- Used mobile application ticketing software to process ticket orders accurately and securely.
- Monitored ticket sales and provided detailed reports to management.
  - Offered advice and assistance to customers, paying attention to special needs or wants.
- Researched and resolved customer ticketing issues to promote satisfaction.
- Greeted customers with smile and provided friendly, knowledgeable service.
  - Provided information about current and future events at facility.
  - Improved operations through consistent hard work and dedication.
- Staffed and scheduled a team of 7 associates on a weekly basis, to ensure coverage and maintain workflow for operational needs.

#### 2007-01 -2015-10

# **Dietary Aide**

Villa Colombo, Toronto, ON

- Distributed food during meal service times while assisting in resident satisfaction in accordance with established schedules and dietary procedures.
- Delivered nourishment and supplements to nurse station for distribution to specific residents.
- Washed plates, cups, serving, and eating utensils and kitchen equipment in commercial dishwasher.
- Set up and prepared cooking supplies and workstations during opening and closing to maximize productivity.
- Maintained strict levels of cleanliness for tables, floors, and prep areas. Cleared tables and removed dishes, trays, and utensils from dining room to dishwashing area.
- Arranged tray and or table settings with proper tableware, condiments, and tray card.
- Upheld efficiency of meal services by pre-setting tables before patients arrived.
- Reported and documented resident changes in consumption or behaviors.

- Followed all food safety regulations while preparing meals for patients.
- Kept all kitchen areas clean, tidy and free of hazards.

# **Education**

2022-09 -	Certificate: Fullstack Web Development
2023-02	University of Toronto - Toronto, ON
2011-05 - 2020-06	Bachelor of Science: Pharmaceutical Chemistry
	University of Toronto - Toronto, ON